
[
    {
        "question": "The Declaration of Independence was adopted on July 4th, 1776, with 12 of the 13 colonies approving it. Which colony originally abstained?",
        "choice1": "Delaware",
        "choice2": "South Carolina",
        "choice3": "New York",
        "choice4": "Virginia",
        "answer": 3,
        "anstext": "C, 'New York'. The real start of the New York, Boston rivaly"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the second President of the United States?",
        "choice1": "James Madison",
        "choice2": "Thomas Jefferson",
        "choice3": "James Monroe",
        "choice4": "John Adams",
        "answer": 4,
        "anstext": "D, 'John Adams'.' Adams's was also the nations 1st Vice President."
    },
    {
        "question": "How long was the Gettysburg address?",
        "choice1": "269 words",
        "choice2": "1233 words",
        "choice3": "10200 words",
        "choice4": "4454 words",
        "answer": 1,
        "anstext": "A, '269 words'. Something to keep in mind before sending an overly long email!"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many years of formal education did Benjamin Franklin have?",
        "choice1": "8",
        "choice2": "11",
        "choice3": "2",
        "choice4": "5",
        "answer": 3,
        "anstext": "C, '2'. Franklin went on to receive honorary doctorates from Harvard, Yale, William and Mary, St. Andrews (Scotland) and Oxford."
    },
    {
        "question": "How much did America pay for the purchase of Alaska in 1867?",
        "choice1": "$10.1 million",
        "choice2": "$7.2 million",
        "choice3": "$999.8k",
        "choice4": "$12.3 million",
        "answer": 2,
        "anstext": "B, '$7.2 million'. That equates to 122 million dollars today, still a bargain."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following were independent countries before joining the United States?",
        "choice1": "Nevada and Utah",
        "choice2": "Texas and California",
        "choice3": "North Dakota and South Dakota",
        "choice4": "Vermont and Texas",
        "answer": 4,
        "anstext": "D, 'Vermont and Texas'. I feel like most people would guess Texas, but Vermont?"
    },
    {
        "question": "What year did American currency officially go off the 'gold standard'?",
        "choice1": "1917",
        "choice2": "1889",
        "choice3": "1933",
        "choice4": "American currency was never backed by gold",
        "answer": 3,
        "anstext": "C, '1933'. Another casualty of the Great Depression."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which right falls under the sixth amendment?",
        "choice1": "Right against illegal searches and seizures",
        "choice2": "Right to freedom of speech",
        "choice3": "Right to a fair and speedy trial",
        "choice4": "Right against self incrimination",
        "answer": 3,
        "anstext": "C, 'Right to a fair and speedy trial'. The 6th amendment guarantees the rights of criminal defendants."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following has the shortest Presidency in U.S. history, totaling just 31 days?",
        "choice1": "William Henry Harrison",
        "choice2": "James Garfield",
        "choice3": "William Howard Taft",
        "choice4": "William McKinley",
        "answer": 1,
        "anstext": "A, 'William Henry Harrison'. Harrison is thought to have died due to complications with pneumonia."
    },
    {
        "question": "What Native American tribe did Sacagawea belong to?",
        "choice1": "Shawnee",
        "choice2": "Shoshone",
        "choice3": "Cherokee",
        "choice4": "Iroquois",
        "answer": 2,
        "anstext": "B, 'Shoshone'. Constantly overlooked, without aid from Native people's the United States as we know it may not exist."
    }
]